Excuse me
不好意思
Mmm
嗯~
sorry
抱歉
I'm not really from around here
我不是这附近的人
Would you mind pointing me in the direction of the shop?
你不介意告诉我这家店往哪儿走吧？
Mm hmm
嗯哼~
I knew you were lost
我就知道你迷路了
Mercury
Mercury
I will seriously pay you to shut up
我真的会付钱请你闭嘴哦
That's not your money
那又不是你的钱
But it could be yours for five minutes of silence
但你只要安静五分钟就是你的了
Mmm....
嗯....
No deal
不成交
Fine
行
Whatever, you want me
反正你需要我跟着
So how much farther?
还有多远啊？
A few blocks
再过几个街区
Ugh....this place is so dull
啊....这地方简直无聊
Eh, I kinda like it
呃，我还挺喜欢
Tall buildings, diverse culture....
高楼大厦，多元文化....
And nice dopey people who are easy to pickpocket
还能随便偷和蔼迟钝之人的钱包
That's every city
每个城市都这样
Oh, Emerald! Master thief!
噢！Emerald！盗贼大师！
Please don't take my money
请别拿走我的钱
I barely have enough to get by
我这点儿钱只能糊口
Hum
口亨
You're no fun today
你今天不好玩
Be right there!
马上就来
Welcome to 'Tukson's Book Trade, home to every book under the sun'
欢迎光临“Tukson的书市，尽收天下书籍”
How may..
想要..
How may I help you?
想要买什么？
Just browsing
只是看看
Actually..
事实上..
I was wondering, do you have any copies of The Thief and The Butcher?
我想问问你们这里有卖《贼与屠夫》么？
Yes we do
我们这有
That's great!
太好了！
Would you..like a copy?
你要..买一本么？
No, just wondering
不，单纯问问
Oh, oh! What about Violet's Garden? In paperback
噢噢！有《紫罗兰花园》么？平装本的
He's got it. Hardback too
他这有，还有精装本的
Ooh, options are nice
唔~能选的都不错
Eh, no pictures
呃，没有图
Hey! Do you have any comics?
喂！你这有漫画么？
Near the front
前排附近
Oh, no, wait
噢，不，等等
What about Third Crusade?
有没有《第三次远征》？
Um..
呃..
I..
我..
don't believe we carry that one
不觉得我们这里有
Oh..
哦..
What was this place called again?
这地方叫啥来着？
'Tukson's Book Trade'
“Tukson的书市”
And..
然后..
You're Tukson?
你是Tukson？
That's right
是我没错
So then I take it..
那我是不是..
that you're the one who came up with the catchphrase?
可以认为就是你想出的这个标语？
Yes
是的
And, what was it again?
那么，是什么来着？
'Tukson's Book Trade, home to every book under the sun'
“Tukson的书市，尽收天下书籍”
Except The Third Crusade
偏偏没有《第三次远征》
It's just a catchphrase
这只是个标语
It's false advertizing!
这是虚假广告！
You shouldn't make a promise you can't keep, Tukson
你不该立下遵守不了的诺言，Tukson
I hear you're planning on leaving
我听说你准备走人
Moving all the way to Vacuo
一直要跑到维基亚
Your brothers in the White Fang wouldn't be happy to hear that
你白牙的弟兄们听到这些应该不会开心吧
And neither are we
我们也不会
You know who we are, don't you?
你知道我们是谁，对吧？
Yes
知道
And you know why we're here?
你明白我们为啥来这儿？
So..
那么..
Are you going to fight back?
你准备反抗么？
Yes!
没错！
What's with that?
那是什么？
I like the pictures
我喜欢这些图
Whatcha doing?
在干啥咩？
Nothing
没啥
Just going over notes from last semester
只是回顾一下上学期的笔记
Lame
不够劲
Ahem
咳咳
Sisters
姐妹们
Friends
朋友们
Weiss
Weiss
Hey!
你够！
Four score and seven minutes ago
在八十七分钟之前
I had a dream
我有一个梦想
This ought to be good
这真是极♂好的
A dream that one day, the four of us will come together as a team
我梦想到有一天我们四人能成为一队
and have the most fun anyone has ever had
而且能度过最有趣的时光
Ever!
最有趣的！
Did you steal my binder?
你偷了我的活页夹？
I am not a crook
我不是小偷
What're you talking about?
你想说些什么？
I'm talking about kicking off the semester with a bang!
我想说我们应该轰轰烈烈地开学
I always kick my semesters off with a Yang!
我从来都是燃着燃着就开学了
Eh? Guys? Am I right?
诶？民那？我没说错吧？
Look guys, it's been a good two weeks
伙伴们，这两周感觉不错
and between more exchange students arriving and the tournament at the end of the year
而随着交换生们越来越多以及年末的锦标赛
Our second semester's going to be great
我们的第二学期会很棒
But classes start back up tomorrow
但明天就又要上课了
Which is why I've taken the time to schedule a series of wonderful events for us today
所以今天我已经花时间计划了一系列精彩活动
I don't know whether to be proud or scared of what you have in store
真不知道该为你的计划骄傲还是担心
I don't know
我不知道
I....think I might sit this one out
我..可能不会参加
Sit out or not
参加与否
I think however we spend this last day, we should do it as a team
我认为无论怎样度过最后一天，都该切团队模式
I got it!
拿到了！
I for one think that..
我个人认为..
Hum, man, that's harsh
哈，伙计，那可真厉害
So then we were fighting side by side
所以我们就并肩作战了
And she was super fast and I threw a banana at the guy
她速度超快，我还朝那家伙丢香蕉
which sounds gross, but it was awesome
听起来恶心，但其实很棒
Nice!
漂亮！
Right?
对吧？
And the best part is, she's a Faunus!
而最赞的是，她是个弗纳人！
But that's a secret, okay?
但这点一定要保密，OK？
Got it..
知道了..
And not a, 'I'm gonna go tell Scarlet the second Sun turns his back secret'
这可不是那种“Sun刚转身一秒我就告诉Scarlet”之类秘密
I'm talking secret secret
我说的是绝密中的绝密
Whoa, chill out man, okay?
哇噢，大哥你冷静点OK？
I got it
我明白了
I got ~ it
我明~白了
You better
明白最好
I just don't wanna screw this up, you know?
我只是不想把这个搞砸了，懂？
The people here are the coolest!
这里的人最酷了！
No offense to you guys
无意冒犯你们
None taken
我不在意
Okay, they're just in here
好了，他们就在里头
I'm really excited for you to meet them
你能见他们我真的很兴奋
So be cool, okay?
所以酷一点，OK？
You're gonna be cool, right?
你会保持帅气的对吧？
Dude
兄弟
Good point
就是这样
A~hahahaha
啊~哈哈哈哈
I'm queen at the castle
我是女王住城堡~
Justice will be swift
正义会立马降临
Justice will be painful
正义会痛苦万分
It will be delicious!
它还非常美味！
Off with their heads
砍下她们的脑袋
Yang, turkey!
Yang，火鸡！
Weiss!
Weiss！
Don't leave me!
别丢下我！
No!
不！
I love these guys
我爱这些家伙
Children, please..
孩子们，拜托..
Do not play with your food
不要拿食物玩耍
Let it go
算了吧
They're supposed to be the defenders of the world
她们应该是这个世界的守护者
And they will be
她们会成为的
But right now they're still children
不过现在她们只是孩子
So why not let them play the part
所以让她们继续当孩子吧
After all..
毕竟..
It isn't the role they'll have forever
她们不会永远是孩子的
Oh, look! She sent the kids again..
噢，看呐！她又把孩子送来了..
This is turning out just like the divorce
这样简直就像离婚嘛
Spare us the thought of be procreating
能不把我们想象成你生的么
That was a joke
开个玩笑而已
And this....
而这个....
Just might tell me where you two have been all day
说不定正好能告诉我你们俩去哪了
What!? Agh!
啥！？啊！
I'm a professional, sweetheart
我是专业的，宝贝儿
Pay attention, maybe you'll learn something
用点心，说不定你还能学个一招半式
Why you have this address?
你怎么会有这个地址？
Wouldn't you like to know?
你会不想知道么？
Yeah, I..I would
对啊，我..我想
Now, where have you been all day?
好了，你们一整天去哪儿了？
Cleaning up your problems
收拾你的烂摊子
One of them, at least
至少办完了一个
I had that under control
那本来就在我掌控之下
Two packed bags and a ticket out of Vale said otherwise
两包行李、一张离开溪谷的票说明没有
Listen you little punk
听着你这小流氓
If it were up to me
如果让我来
I would take you and your little street rat friend here and I would..
我就会把你和你那过街老鼠的朋友给..
Do what, Roman?
给怎么样，Roman？
Hahaha..
哈哈哈..- -
I'd, uh..
我就，呃..
Not kill them?
不杀他们？
Cinder!
Cinder！
I thought I made it clear that you were to eliminate the would-be runaway
我以为我早说清了要你去解决那个差点叛逃的
I was going to..
我本来要..
He was going to escape to Vacuo
他本来要逃去维基亚了
Mercury and I decided to take it upon ourselves to kill the rat
Mercury和我决定自己动手解决那只老鼠
I think he was some sort of cat, actually
其实我觉得他是某种猫科的
What? Like a puma?
啥？美洲狮？
Yeah, there you go
没错，就那个
Quiet
安静
Did I not specifically instruct you two to keep your hands clean while in Vale?
难道我没特别命令你们在溪谷时手别染血么？
I just thought..
我只是想..
Don't think, obey
不要想, 服从命令
Yes ma'am. It won't happen again
是，夫人，不会再这样了
And you..
还有你..
Hahahaha~
哈哈哈哈~
Why wasn't this job done sooner?
为什么这个活不早点做完？
Uh..0v0
呃..0v0
Eh..-v-?
呃..-v-?
Eh..-w-!?
呃..-w-!?
EH 0w0!!
呃0w0！！
Sorry if I've been little busy stealing every speck of Dust in the Kingdom!
还真是抱歉，我忙着去偷这王国的每一粒尘晶
You're an inspiration to every punk with a gun and a ski mask
你可是每个拿枪带滑雪面罩的流氓们的榜样
Look around, kid
四下看看，小鬼
I've got this town running scared
我让城里笼罩了一层恐惧
Police camping out at every corner
警察在每个角落扎营
Dust prices through the roof
尘晶的价格飞涨
and we're sitting pretty on an old warehouse
而我们舒服地坐在这旧仓库里
with more Dust crystals, vials and rounds than we know what to do with
守着一堆尘晶晶体、小瓶、弹药不知道该干嘛
Speaking of which
说到这里
If you guys wouldn't mind filling me in on your grand master plan
如果不介意让我多了解点你们的大师级计划
It might, actually make my next string of roberries go little smoother!
确实有可能让我接下来的一系列抢劫更顺利
Oh, Roman~ Have a little faith
噢，Roman~有点信心嘛
You'll know what you need when you need to know
当需要你知道时，自然会知道需要什么了
Besides, we're done with Dust
此外，尘晶的活干完了
Okay, then what now?
好吧，那现在呢？
We're moving
我们转移
Have the White Fang clear out this building
让白牙把这栋建筑清干净
I'll send you details and coordinates tonight
今晚我会发给你详情和坐标
Coordinates?
坐标？
We're proceeding to Phase Two
我们正在进入第二阶段
There's a point where it tips
There's a point where it tips
There's a point where it breaks
There's a point where it breaks
There's a point where it bends
There's a point where it bends
And a point we just can't take anymore
And a point we just can't take anymore
There's a line that we'll cross
There's a line that we'll cross
And there's no return
And there's no return
There's a time and a place
There's a time and a place
No bridges left to burn anymore
No bridges left to burn anymore
We can't just wait with lives at stake
We can't just wait with lives at stake
Until they think we're ready
Until they think we're ready
Our enemies are gathering
Our enemies are gathering
The storm is growing deadly
The storm is growing deadly
Now it's time to say goodbye
Now it's time to say goodbye
To the things we loved
To the things we loved
And the innocence of youth
And the innocence of youth
How the time seemed to fly
How the time seemed to fly
From our carefree lives
From our carefree lives
And the solitude and peace we always knew
And the solitude and peace we always knew
BRB
BRB
This SUB is presented by Baidu RWBY Bar Creator: sbz_kid
本字幕由百度RWBY吧提供 片源/翻译/后期：sbz_kid